『昇らない太陽』—　The Pillows
她-她-她從哪裡來?!
W-W-Where did she come from?!
酷——美—— 她來了！
Hi...do...mi -- Aah! -- is here!
對了！我們今天也要吃掉彼此呢！
Oh, yeah! We're gonna devour each other today!
我和我的朋友們！
Me and my friends!
我的朋友們就是
And by friends I mean my former classmates,
我從來沒有說過話的老同學！
whom I never had a single conversation with!
好棒！
Yatta!
呃 喂？怎麼這樣！
Uh, hey? How awful!
我的朋友一個都沒來！
None of my friends are here!
這樣我不就沒辦法感受被吃掉的痛苦了嗎?!
How am I supposed to feel the pain of being eaten now?!
將我的體內和外界分隔開的
The single layer of skin that divides the inside
那一層皮膚 我想讓它被剝落！
of my body from the outside, I want it peeled off!
我想讓它被撕下 被啃食掉！
I want it clawed off! I want it gnawed off.
我好想讓我的皮膚被猛地扯開
I just want the whole thing ripped open with one swift tear!
我被撕裂的皮膚所感受到的冰冷的空氣是世界的溫度
The cold air that I feel on my cracked and torn skin is the temperature of the world!
喂！酷美！酷美！
Hey, Hidomi! Hidomi!
我跟你說過要當心騎 Vespa 的女人！
I told you to watch out for the Vespa woman!
我讓你留神的！
I told you to be careful.
為什麼不聽我的話！你應該記著我的警告！
Why didn't you listen to me?! You should've heeded my warning!
小心！
Hey, look out!
看！
Pay attention!
我受不了了
I can't take it!
打水漂
本字幕由 SweetSub 製作　僅做交流學習之用途
翻校：ピロピラ ピロコ　其它：tastySugar
晴子老師 你真是太棒了！
Miss Haruko, you are seriously the best!
Yoohoo 男生們？
Yoohoo? Male students?
有沒有人願意幫老師塗防曬乳？
Does one of you boys wanna help their teacher put on sunscreen?
-來了！ -等等
-Coming! -Hold on.
喂 森 看看時間 你沒有忘了吧？
Hey, Mori? Look at the time. Aren't you forgetting something?
你不是說你的女朋友馬上要來嗎？
Didn't you say your girlfriend was coming soon?
你跟我們說過你有個女朋友的
You told us that you had a girlfriend,
我們來沙灘上就是因為這個
and we came all the way to the beach 'cause of it.
可一定要讓我們見到她
So we'd better get to meet her.
那必須的！我的朋友們！
Of course! Fear not, my fellow friends!
我只是忘了時間而已！
I merely lost track of the time!
跟我走 這邊！
This way, men! Follow me!
好吧 雲雀弄 你來幫我塗
All right, fine. Hibaji. You'll have to do it.
你來塗也行 仁由
I'm fine with you doing it, as well, Jinyu.
同志們！
Comrades!
這是我的女朋友
This is my girlfriend.
來認識一下愛子
Come say hello to Aiko.
快 跟他們打個招呼
Go on, say something to them!
初次見面
Uh, nice to meet you.
我和森正在交往中
I'm dating your good friend Mori.
我的名字是愛子
My name's Aiko.
啊 好害羞
Ah! I'm so embarrassed!
她好完美！淑女！
She's perfect! Such a lady!
她不喝酒 不說髒話 也不出汗！
She doesn't drink, swear, or sweat!
難以置信吧 這麼熱的天！
Can you believe it?! This hot and no sweat!
抱歉我想問一下
Excuse me?
你為什麼會想和森交往？
What was it that made you wanna date Mori?
那個…
Oh. Well...
因為我非常喜歡他
because I really like him.
啊 好害羞
Oh, I'm so embarrassed!
你手裡拿的是什麼東西？
What is that thing you've been holding?
這個？這…就是一個花盆
Oh, this? T-This is just a flower pot.
這我知道 但是你為什麼會拿著花盆？
I figured, but why do you have it?
這是一株用於情感支持的植物
It's an emotional support plant.
真的有用嗎？
Does it work?
這不是很可愛嗎?!
Isn't that just cute?!
別這麼說！好害羞！
Don't say that! It's embarrassing!
也許看不出來 但是這盆植物還挺貴的
It may not look like it, but this plant was expensive.
好吧 我還真看不出來
Yeah? I would've never guessed.
啊！好可愛！
Ah! So cute!
油乎乎的！多少防曬指數的？
So oily! What SPF was that?!
呀 這是助曬油
Oh. This is tanning oil.
這是什麼?!
It's what?
哼 對我還有意見
Still holding a grudge, I see.
比起過去三個月
Just for the past three months.
你對我們的纏擾
Ever since you've been stalking me.
這不算什麼
This is nothing.
你想要的 你已經得到過一次了
You've already gotten what you wanted once before.
是時候結束了
It's time you quit.
放手吧
Just give up.
想的美
No way.
我需要滿足心願才能完成——
I need to fulfill my wish in order to fulfill my --
好害羞！
How embarrassing!
攻擊——
Attack number...
一號
ichi!
好害羞！
So embarrassing!
不如現在先停戰吧？
So, why don't we call a truce for now?
不管你們準備好沒有 你們的老師要參戰了！
Ready or not, your teacher's coming!
那個女人…
That woman over there...
Here's the balls!
球來了！
她想要什麼？
What does she want?
球來了！
Here comes the balls!
那個女人和我相同
That woman's the same as me.
『Thank you, my twilight 』—　The Pillows
接球！
Receive!
嗶 嗶 嗶
Bip, bip, bip!
下一個誰來？
Who wants to go next?!
所以 仁由
So, uh, Jinyu...
你想要的是什麼？
What is it that you want?
我曾經和一個很棒的人在一起
I was once with someone amazing.
他巨大 強大 那樣令人不可思議
He was big, strong, and just simply amazing.
和他在一起 我可以在宇宙中自由翱翔 永不停止
With him, one can fly around anywhere in space forever.
但是後來他突然消失了
But then he suddenly disappeared.
他拋棄了我
He abandoned me.
結果到頭來 我根本無法與他相比對等
Turns out, in the end, I just wasn't his equal.
我不能滿足他 單靠我是不夠的…
I'm not enough for him. Not by myself...
然而 我們還是繼續尋找他
And yet, we still continue to look for him.
「我們」？
We?
來呀！
Bring it on!
晴子老師也在找嗎？
Miss Haruko is searching, too?
追尋只是因為無法抓獲
You chase something simply because you can't catch it.
想要觸碰 只是因為知道自己觸碰不到
Want to touch it, 'cause you know you can't.
你也一定有過這樣的經歷吧
You must have experienced something like that in your life?
你在問我嗎？
You're asking me?
酷美真正想要的是什麼呢？
What is that Hidomi really wants?
我…
Well...
實話說 我沒有什麼想要的
truth is, there's really nothing that I want.
不敢相信你能接到球！
Can't believe you could play like that!
『天使みたいにキミは立ってた』—　The Pillows
真可謂是青春啊
The blue spring of adolescence.
也許這是我們的友誼的延伸？
Perhaps this is an extension of our friendship?
遲來的青春 你覺得呢？
Delayed adolescence, if you will?
我不介意你對我們的關係有新的看法
I'm content with you changing your mind about our relationship.
但這不意味著你可以插手酷美的事情
But regardless, it still doesn't mean that you can have Hidomi.
繼續爭鬥毫無意義
No point in fighting anymore.
真的如此嗎？
Huh is that so
洗腦抑制機制
Brainwashing suppression mechanism...
他們提前採取了措施
They took extra measures ahead of time.
你不覺得很讚嗎？ 我們在一起多開心啊！
Isn't this just great? Aren't we having the best time?
你覺得我們能堆多高？
How high do you think we can make it?
隨便你在哪裡挖
-Dig wherever you want.
還有…
-By the way...
…我不明白這樣有什麼好玩的
...I'm not really seeing the fun in all of this.
啊！該去尿尿了！該走的時候就不要等
Ah! Tinkle time! When you gotta go, you gotta go.
我走了！
And I'm going!
你不算去游泳嗎？
So, are you not planning on swimming?
蛤？不
Huh? No.
都已經到沙灘上了 你卻不想游泳嗎？
Oh. You're not, even though we came to the beach to swim?
-那你呢？-嗯？
-And what about you. -Excuse me?
你帶了泳衣嗎？
Did you bring your swimsuit?
這不是我們事先說好的內容
That's not what we agreed to this time.
你們看到了嗎？
Did you see that just now?!
喂！愛子！
Hey, Aiko!
看到我有多厲害了嗎？
Did you witness my awesomeness?!
等一下 雲雀弄在哪裡？
Wait a sec. Where's Hibajiri?
不行 找不到她
No use. I can't find her.
我想不出她能去哪裡
I wonder where she could've gone.
晴子老師也不見了
Miss Haruko is missing, as well.
也許她們沒跟我們說就自己回家了？
Maybe they went home without telling us?
如果她們沒有回家怎麼辦?!
And what do we do if they didn't?!
再找一次！把沙灘從頭到尾再搜一遍！
Let's look again! Do one more sweep of the beach!
森…
Mori…
我必須回家了
I'm gonna need to go home soon.
啊！對不起！我忘了你的那件事
Huh? Oh, right! Sorry! I forgot about your thing.
對對對對
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
我去去就回 把愛子送到車站
-I'll be right back. I'm just gonna walk Aiko to the station.
那好吧
-Oh. Okay. -Thank you.
謝謝 你人真好
You're such a nice person.
易如反掌 哈哈哈
It's no biggie!
我把話說清楚 我要收加班費！
Just so you know, I'll be charging you overtime!
我很抱歉
I am sorry about that
-錢呢  -呃 在這
- Give it.  - Uh, here.
-拿好  -一定
- Hold this. - Sure.
我扮演的角色還對你的口味嗎？
So, was the character I created to your liking?
是的 非常完美 你超棒的
Yes, it was perfect! You were fantastic!
火車即將離開站台
The train will be leaving the station momentarily.
OK  正好
Okay. It's all there.
你們男生覺得害羞怯懦的女孩子很可愛 是嗎？
You boys think it's so cute when girls are all shy and timid, am I right?
對了 那盆草你留著吧
Oh, by the way, the plant's yours to keep.
這是給你的禮物！
A present for you!
哦 謝謝！你真——
Oh. Thank you. That is so ni--
才怪
No, it's not.
你就假裝是用信封裡的東西換了那個
Let's just pretend that we exchanged what's in this envelope for that.
我可不想讓別人知道我在搞租賃女友的生意
I wouldn't want people finding out that I'm running a rent-a-date.
所以說…我從你那裡買了這個
So... I bought this from you.
拜拜 或者隨便你
Bye. Or whatever.
馬！
Maa!
『白い夏と緑の自転車 赤い髪と黒いギター』—　The Pillows
-當你還小的時候… -誰?!
-When you were a kid... -Who's there?!
你有沒有試著畫過自己和家人一起去看煙火
Did you ever try drawing a picture of going to see fireworks with your family,
但卻畫不出來？
only to fail?
仁由 是你嗎？
It's Jinyu, right?
告訴我 酷美—我是說 雲雀弄和你在一起嗎？
Tell me, is Hidomi -- I mean, is Hibajiri with you?
你想要畫出你看見的無數光點
You try to draw the countless specks of light that you saw,
但是重現夜空的唯一方法
but the only way to recreate the night sky
就是用黑色鉛筆把一切都塗上顏色
is to color everything in with a black pencil.
它們照亮了夜空
They were lighting up that dark sky
絢爛奪目
and they were so colorful and beautiful.
你在說什麼?!你怎麼不——
What are you talking about?! Why won't you--
所有美麗的事物最終都將消逝
All beautiful things eventually fade away.
哦 第一顆星
Oh, the first star.
摸來摸去 摸來摸去
Goodie. Goodie, goodie, goodie
請住手
Please stop.
我們進一步互相了解對方吧
Let's get to know each other better.
住手！
Stop it!
是這裡嗎？
Is it here?
不要 住手 求求你
No. Stop, please.
行了 笑話我吧
Go on, laugh at me.
別笑了！
Stop laughing!
哎呀
Oh, my.
看來你原本是打算出來好好玩的
Looks like you were planning on having fun today.
幫我個忙吧
Help me out here.
告訴我應該摸哪裡 才能讓你溢出
Just tell me where to hit you, so you'll overflow.
溢出？
Overflow?
你為什麼要這麼做 晴子老師
What are you doing, Miss Haruko?!
什麼 居然是從這傢伙裡面出來的？
What? It's coming out of that one?
我不知道你是什麼東西 但是…
I don't know what the hell you are, but...
去救雲雀弄！
...go save Hibajiri!
真是悲慘得不忍直視 森！
It was too painful to watch, Mori!
拜託你別哭了行不行？
Will you please stop crying?
你讓我感覺更可悲了
You're just making me feel even more pathetic.
不！
No!
上帝啊 為什麼？為什麼會這樣？
Oh, God, why? Why is this happening?
喂 愛子
Hey, Aiko?
你知道這個房間的花盆到哪裡去了嗎？
Do you know what happened to the flower pot that was in this room?
不曉得
No clue.
這裡是代號眼罩
This is code name Eye Patch.
有新的情況嗎？-我這裡有點小麻煩
Do you have an update? -I have a slight problem.
什麼麻煩？
What?
I can't locate the "flower pot."
我找不到「花盆」了
滾你——
Son-of-a...!
酷美——
Hidomi...
聽著 井出
Listen, Ide.
只有你可以救酷美
You're the only one who can save Hidomi.
在後座
Back here.
你怎麼搞成這樣？
What happened to you?
算了
Never mind.
我們還有其他事情要做
We have more important things to deal with.
酷美在那個東西裡面 那不正常 對吧?!
Hidomi is inside of that thing! That's not normal, right?!
實話說 最近不正常的事情有不少
Truth be told, there have been plenty of things that haven't been normal lately.
但這次不一樣 這是不可接受的！
But this is different. This is unacceptable!
拜託了仁由！你得做點什麼！
Please! You have to do something, Jinyu!
如果你畫不出煙火 那麼…
If you are unable to draw fireworks, well then...
什麼？
What?
就向天空發射煙火吧
Try shooting one in the air.
再試一次  多少次都行直到成功為止！
Do it again! As many times as you need!
我改主意了  你應該是煙火才對
On second thought, maybe you should be the firework instead?
『Freebee Honey』—　The Pillows
啊 很好
Ah, yeah!
酷斃了
This is amazing!
啊！逮到你了！
Ah! Got you now!
喂！雲雀弄！
Hey! Hibajiri!
雲雀弄！雲雀弄！
Hibajiri! Hibajiri!
該死！我該怎麼做?!
Shit! What am I supposed to do?!
唔…她還沒被滿足
Hmm. She doesn't have enough yet.
晴子老師
Miss Haruko.
驕傲…？撒嬌…？
A tundra Sundera
傲嬌？唔…
Tsundere? Hmm.
這個女孩是那種類型吧？
This girl is that type, isn't she?
我說得沒錯吧？
Am I right?
閉嘴
Shut up.
雲雀弄！啊！
Hibajiri! Ah!
雲雀弄！雲雀弄！
Hibajiri! Hibajiri!
我只想要你能醒過來
I just want you to wake up.
喊她的名字可沒有用
Calling her name won't help.
讓你可靠的老師來吧
Leave it up to your good old teach.
住手！
Stop it!
那就取下她的耳機
Then take off her headphones.
去呀 別害羞
Go on, don't be shy.
不要擔心
No need to worry.
你的聲音會傳遞給她的
Your voice will reach her.
別做！別被騙了！
It's a trick! Don't do it!
你能夠得到的
You can reach it.
這在她的身體深處
It's deep inside of her.
不如我們一起來 OK?
Why don't we do it together, OK?
我不用你幫忙！我自己來！
I don't need your help! I'll do it myself!
『Fool on the Planet』—　The Pillows
雲雀弄！喂！雲雀弄！該死的！
Hibajiri! Hey! Hibajiri! Dammit!
我讓你不要那樣做的！
I told you not to do that!
如果你…
If you...
應急系統被啟動了
The emergency system has been activated.
沒有任何辦法停下它
There's nothing you can do to stop it.
天啊
Ah, geez.
可惡 那些混蛋 真夠狡猾的
Damn, they're so sneaky. Those bastards.
這都是因為你試圖誘惑那個男生
This is all because you tried to tempt that guy.
沒錯 晴子老師試圖…
That's right, Miss Haruko tried to...
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
她…她從哪裡來？
Whe…where she comes from.......
是…是我 酷 酷美
It's -- it's me, Hi-Hidomi...
我來了
is... right here.
什麼？喂！
What? Hey!
雲雀弄！我不明白！
Hibajiri! I don't understand!
求求你 醒過來 說點什麼！
Please, wake up! Say something!
告訴我這幅景象是怎麼回事？
Tell me what's wrong with this picture?
看起來就像 就像…
Take a look. It's like...it's like...
說什麼都行！你的話到底什麼意思！
Anything! What do you mean by that.....
對不起 我覺得都是我的錯
I'm sorry! I feel like this is all my fault!
我想這也許就是所謂青春吧
I guess that's what they call adolescence.
求求你 把眼睛睜開 雲雀弄！
Please open your eyes! Please, Hibajiri!
只剩一個選擇 拉哈路
Only one option left, Raharu.
看來只能正面突破了
I supposed I'll just have to bust on in.
沒錯 我們的目的也許不同
Right. While our objectives may be different,
我們卻有著同一個目標
our target remains the same.
Medical Mechanica
Medical Mechanica.